Jamila Maqsoudi

Master of Computer Applications (202)743-9855

<u>jmaqsoudi</u>90@gmail.com | <u>Jamila Maqsoudi</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>jmaqsoudi</u> (<u>Jamila Maqsoudi</u>) (<u>github.com</u>)

SUMMARY

A highly motivated detail-oriented Full Stack Developer with in-depth knowledge of languages and development tools, and total 5 plus years of experience in analysis, development, designing, modification, integration, testing, documentation, and troubleshooting of critical software systems. Efficient team member who worked remarkably as part of a team with people coming from different organizational levels and diverse backgrounds. Equally successful working independently on time-sensitive projects and tasks. Grade A graduate (Computer Application) from Savitribai Phule Pune University, India (2015-2018).

TECHNOLOGIES

- Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Angular, Bootstrap
- Back-End: Node.js, Spring Boot, RESTful APIs, Java, Microservices
- Databases & Tools: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQL Server, Dbeaver, MySQL Workbench, pgAdmin
- Design Patterns: Factory Method, Abstract Factory, Prototype, Singleton, Template
- Testing & Quality Assurance: JUnit, Unit Testing, Postman API Development Testing Tool, Cucumber, POM Framework, TestNG
- DevOps & Cloud Technologies: AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub
- Other Tools & Technologies: Agile Scrum Development Methodology, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Keycloak Server user Authentication/Authorization, Anaconda, Star UML.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Mar 2020-Dec 2021

National Statistics and Information Authority(NSIA), Kabul, Afghanistan

- Collaborated with senior developers to research, design, and code the eBreshna Web Application.
- Used Spring Boot and Angular to develop responsive interfaces and build microservices that efficiently handle complex operations.
- Implemented KeyClack Server, OAuth 2.0 protocol for a secure central authentication and authorization of the users.
- Used DBeaver and MySQL Workbench for querying, editing, and managing data.
- Utilized Postman for testing, and documenting APIs.
- Coded and implemented python scripts for data migration using Anaconda.
- Utilized Docker and Kubernetes containerization technologies to package and deploy the service in a consistent and reliable manner.
- Worked partially with AWS (Amazon Web Services) to deploy and manage eBreshna in the cloud, which included leveraging services like EC2, S3, and Lambda to build scalable and reliable systems.
- Used Hibernate JPA to map database tables to Java classes and performed CRUD operations on the database.

• Debugged performance issues, reviewed and refactored existing code.

Software Developer & Testing Engineer Nov 2018-Mar 2020

Ministry of Communication & IT, Kabul, Afghanistan

- Contributed with senior developers to create microservices and a scalable and maintainable backend for the system, implementing various features such as user authentication and authorization, data storage and retrieval, and API integration using Spring Boot.
- Used Angular, TypeScript, and HTML, CSS to create component-based, responsive user-friendly and interactive user interfaces, implemented two-way data binding, dependency injections, pipes, directives, services.
- Used postman to test APIs and ensure system operability.
- Contributed in testing, including architecture, performance evaluation, and project planning, also
 managed test processes, coordinated reviews, and prepared reports while ensuring proper
 documentation and data archiving.
- Implemented Hibernate JPA and performed CRUD operations on the database.
- Performed necessary refactoring to enhance code quality and performance.

Software Developer Intern Jan 2018-May 2018

LeanQuality Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India

- Collaborated with the team to design, code, and implement the Customer Relationship Management System (CRM).
- Utilized technologies including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for creating the structure and styling of web pages.
- Utilized Java to create a scalable and maintainable back-end.
- Utilized MySQL for database management.
- Actively participated in code reviews and refactorings to maintain code quality and adhere to best practices.
- Contributed to the documentation of the system.

Database Specialist May 2013-May 2015

Ministry of Finance, Kabul, Afghanistan

- Collaborated with the team to manage and monitor databases using MySQL and PostgreSQL to ensure data integrity, availability, and security.
- Actively controlled access permissions and privileges, implementing authentication and authorization mechanisms using mysqldump and pg_dump.
- Provided technical support, identified and resolved issues.
- Monitored database performance using MySQL Workbench and psql, identified and resolved bottlenecks, and optimized SQL queries and database schema to improve system performance.
- Actively contributed to documentation of the database system.

ACADEMIC & PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

eBreshna (National Statistics and Information Authority, 2020-2021): It is a comprehensive Power Management System that encompasses a range of essential components, as Consumer Master for

enrolling consumers through online and offline forms, Billing for generating accurate bills, Metering for measuring energy usage, and Consumer Support for addressing customer queries/concerns.

Technologies used: Spring boot, Angular, PostgreSql, KeyCloak Server, JPA and Hibernate, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS Services

eNID (Ministry of Communication and IT, 2018): The Electronic National ID is a groundbreaking digital data management project in Afghanistan, leveraging the power of data science to manage and analyze large volumes of information. It represents a significant milestone in the country's efforts to harness the potential of big data, with the potential to generate valuable insights that can be used to advance the welfare of the people.

Technologies used: Spring Tool Suite(STS), Angular, SQL Developer, Data Modeler, Unit Testing, Postman API Development Testing Tool, Cucumber, POM Framework, TestNG

CRM (LeanQuality Solutions (I) Pvt. Ltd., 2018): It is a powerful tool designed to manage interactions with both existing and potential customers. With its ability to centralize and organize customer data, this system enables businesses to gain a deeper understanding of customer needs and preferences, allowing them to deliver personalized experiences and targeted marketing campaigns that resonate with their audience.

Technologies used: Eclipse, Java, React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL Database

Mini Reminder (Savitribai Phule Pune University, Fergusson College, 2017): It's a small, fast, and simple application to remember important events like birthdays, anniversaries, renewals, etc.

Technologies used: Eclipse, Java, React, HTML, CSS, MySQL Database

School Social Media Platform (Savitribai Phule Pune University, Fergusson College, 2016): It's a platform for connecting and sharing information among students of MCA Department. This includes user registration and authentication, profile creation, posting and commenting on updates, sending and receiving messages, creating and joining groups, and searching for users.

Technologies used: ASP.NET, C#, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL Database

Online Real Estate (Bakhtar University, 2013): It's a web application that one can use to buy, sell, rent and manage properties online instead of getting physically involved.

Technologies used: PHPStorm, CSS, HTML, Java Script, MySQL Database

School Management System (Bakhtar University, 2012): It's an application that simplifies the various school administrations and colleges and brings together administrators, teachers, students, and parents. It is a web-based application for the effective and efficient administration of a school.

Technologies used: ASP.NET, C#, CSS, HTML, MySQL Database

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Savitribai Phule Pune University, Fergusson College, Master of Computer Application (MCA), Software Engineering, 2018, GPA: 3.33

Bakhtar University, Bachelor of Computer Science (BCS),

Programming, 2013, GPA: 2.30

National Institute of Management and Administration (NIMA), Diploma for Public Administration and Management, Information Technology, 2011, GPA: 3.21

American University of Afghanistan,
Certificate, CCNA, 2014
Certificate, CompTIA Network+, 2013
Certificate, MCITP Enterprise Administration, 2013
Certificate, CompTIA A+, 2012

*United Nations Institute for Training and Research (UNITAR),*Certificate, Leading Inclusive 4IR: Empowering Women in Afghanistan for the Future of Work through Digital Reskilling, 2021